Experience a twist on happily ever after.
Spellbound is a animation, fantasy, family film directed by Vicky Jenson.
When a powerful spell turns her parents into giant monsters, a teenage princess
must journey into the wild to reverse the curse before it's too late.
Ellian (voice), played by Rachel Zegler.
Chilo (voice), played by Miguel Bernardeau.
Orsola (voice), played by Giovanna Bush.
Lumbrian Soldier (voice), played by Dennis Stowe.
Nazara (voice), played by Jenifer Lewis.
Flink (voice), played by Dee Bradley Baker.
Spellbound is a 2024 American animated musical fantasy comedy film directed by Vicky Jenson from a screenplay by Julia Miranda and
the writing team of Lauren Hynek and Elizabeth Martin, based on a story conceived by Jenson, Hynek, and Martin.
It features music composed by Alan Menken, who also wrote the songs
with longtime collaborator and lyricist Glenn Slater.
Produced by Skydance Animation, the film features the voices of Rachel Zegler, John Lithgow,
Jenifer Lewis, Tituss Burgess, Nathan Lane, Javier Bardem, and Nicole Kidman.
Set in the world of magic known as Lumbria, the story follows Princess Ellian (Zegler) who must break the
spell that has turned her parents (Bardem and Kidman) into monsters and split her kingdom in two.
The project, initially titled Split, was announced in July 2017, shortly after Skydance Animation
was formed in March 2017, with Paramount Pictures scheduling distribution for 2019.
The film subsequently underwent changes, such as release dates, with Jenson later announced as the director, and
the film's title changed to The Unbreakable Spell, before eventually getting to its current title.
The film was acquired by Apple TV+ in December 2020, before
Netflix took over the rights in October 2023.
Much of the main voice cast signed on in June 2022,
following Zegler's casting in April 2022.
Production was done remotely during the COVID-19 pandemic.
Spellbound premiered at the Paris Theater in New York City on November
11, 2024, and was released via Netflix on November 22.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of magic, kingdom, musical, kids, 3d animation.
The tone is lighthearted.